icfo.eu 2018-12-29

# ICFO - Privacy Policy

### TERMS OF USE OF THE WEBSITE www.icfo.eu

The website www.icfo.eu (the “Website”) is owned and operated by the Institut de Ciències Fotòniques ("ICFO") with registered address at Av. Carl Friedrich Gauss, 3, (08860) Castelldefels, Barcelona, Spain, registered before the Foundations Registry (Registre de Fundacions) of the Generalitat de Catalunya under number 1651, telephone number (+34) 93 553 4002, e-mail address [secretariat@icfo.eu](mailto:secretariat@icfo.eu).

In the moment that you, as a user of the Website, utilize any of the services available on or organised by the Website, you accept in its entirety the terms which have been laid out for your information in this Policy, as well as in the [Privacy Policy](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-1) and in the [Cookies Policy](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-2).

In this regard, by using the Website, we understand that you have read, understood and accepted these conditions, which shall be legally binding for you. If you do not agree, please do not use our Website.

#### Use of the Website

Our Website shall not be used in any way that breaches any law or regulation, or that has any unlawful or immoral purpose or effect.

If you use a feature of this Website that allows you to upload or post material, or to make contact with other users of this Website, you must ensure that all such contributions are compliant with applicable law and that they do not breach any intellectual property, privacy or confidentiality rights of a third party, or any legal or contractual duty owed to a third party. We will not be responsible, or liable to any third party, for the content or accuracy of any material posted by you or any other user of this Website. We have the right to remove any information you upload to our Website if, in our opinion, it does not comply with these Terms of Use or otherwise within our complete discretion.

You must not misuse our Website by knowingly introducing viruses, trojans, worms, logic bombs, keystroke loggers, spyware, adware, malware and/or any other harmful programs or similar computer code designed to adversely affect the operation of any computer software or hardware, or which is otherwise malicious or technologically harmful.

If you are provided with a username, password or any other piece of information in relation to your use of this Website, you must treat such information as confidential. Such information is to be used exclusively by you, who is responsible for storing it, protecting its confidentiality and using it appropriately. ICFO shall not be responsible for any damages resulting from the misuse of this information and shall remain free to cancel or modify access at its sole discretion.

ICFO reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to terminate your access to all or part of this Website without notice.

#### Limitation of liability

Information on the Website is provided on an “as is” basis, with no warranty that it is exact or up to date. As a result, to the fullest extent permitted by law, ICFO shall not be held responsible for any harm that may result from the use of this information nor for the lawfulness of content provided by suppliers, users and other third parties in their use of the website.

ICFO takes appropriate steps to detect computer viruses but it cannot guarantee that the Website is free from malfunctions, defects, bugs and viruses; or that the Website will operate correctly and as expected, at any given time. We shall not be liable for any loss or damage which occurs as a result of any malware. You are responsible for protecting your devices with appropriate technical measures.

Our Website may contain links to other websites, which may be owned and operated by third parties. Please be informed that this Terms of Use do not cover those websites and ICFO shall not be held responsible for their content. Moreover, if you access those websites, their operators may collect and use personal information from you in accordance with their own policies.

#### Intellectual property rights

ICFO name and logo, as well as other distinctive signs (whether image or text) that appear on this website (including the domain name) are the exclusive property of ICFO and are duly protected under Intellectual Property laws and regulations. Ownership implies the exclusive right to use these distinctive signs in the course of trade and to impede unauthorized use by third parties.

Content, text, photographs, designs, logos, images, sounds, videos, animations, recordings, computer software, source code and, in general, any intellectual creation on this Website, as well as the Website as a multimedia artwork, are protected by intellectual property laws.

Any use of the Website’s content requires ICFO’s previous written authorization.

#### Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy

Please refer to our [Privacy Policy](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-1) to know how we collect and use your personal information and to our [Cookies Policy](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-2) to find out more information about the cookies that we use.

#### Severability and amendments

Should one or more provisions of these Terms of Use be or become invalid or unenforceable in whole or in part, this shall not affect the validity and enforceability of the remaining provisions of these Terms of Use.

We may change our Terms of Use from time to time, which will be published on our Website, from when they will become effective.

#### Governing law and Jurisdiction

These Terms of Use and any non-contractual disputes or claims are governed by Spanish law and submitted to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of Barcelona.

### PRIVACY POLICY

ICFO endeavours to safeguard and protect the privacy and confidentiality of your personal data pursuant to applicable laws (GDPR) and implementing regulations.

To help achieve this goal ICFO has drafted this Privacy Policy, which describes how we collect, use and otherwise handle “Personal Information” we receive from you when you use this Website and explains the circumstances in which we may transfer this to others.

“Personal Information” as referred in this Policy consists in information such as email, telephone number and address you provide as well as your personal preferences, choices and requirements specific to particular requests or services.

Our Privacy Policy must be read together with any other legal notices or terms and conditions also available on our Website ([Terms of use](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-0) and [Cookies Policy](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-2)).

If you have any questions in relation to this Privacy Policy, or if you would like to contact us to exercise your rights as stated in this Privacy Policy, you may contact us to the address, telephone or e-mail below stated.

#### Website responsible

The website www.icfo.eu (the “Website”) is owned and operated by the Institut de Ciències Fotòniques ("ICFO") with registered address at Av. Carl Friedrich Gauss, 3, (08860) Castelldefels, Barcelona, Spain, registered before the Foundations Registry (Registre de Fundacions) of the Generalitat de Catalunya under number 1651, telephone number (+34) 93 553 4002, e-mail address [secretariat@icfo.eu](mailto:secretariat@icfo.eu).

#### Collection of Personal Information

Provided your previous consent or the need to fulfil a legal obligation, ICFO requests Personal Information that is appropriate for, relevant to and necessary for the purpose for which it has been collected, when required to:

  * Provide you with services and/or information: to satisfy your requests and respond to your queries. This includes the information provided through the forms available in the Website for accessing employment positions, scholarships and other openings available at ICFO or participating in ICFO organized events.
  * For marketing purposes: to send institutional communications, in order to keep you informed of events, developments, news and activities carried out by ICFO, to handle the sending of information and documentation we believe may be of interest to you, to help improve our services via communications, surveys or requests and to contact you when this is required for satisfying any of the mentioned purposes. You can of course refuse to receive any such communication at any time by contacting ICFO or by using the “unsubscribe” option included in any marketing e-mail or other marketing material received
  * Provide technical support to users
  * Host and maintain the Website

Personal data will be kept by ICFO as long as you do not request its deletion.

ICFO does not process any Personal Information for individuals under 13 years old who are asked not to provide any personal data via any of the interactive forms and other contact methods available on the website.

#### Cookies

ICFO may implement browsing surveys and traceability systems and/or devices in order to collect information for the purposes of establishing general user trends and improving browsing (e.g. cookies).

Information obtainable from browsing may include: the Internet service provider’s domain name in order to ascertain the geographic origins of the computers accessing the web; Internet addresses which redirect navigation to ICFO’s website in order to analyse and evaluate sources of interest in ICFO; browsing dates and times in order to optimise browsing according to traffic peak/off-peak hours; daily web traffic to each section of the web. The tools employed to analyse browser activity have been designed to conduct statistical surveys, and will not be used to identify individual visitors. Please, refer to our [Cookies Policy](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-2) for more information.

#### Communication of information to third parties

Some services that we provide require the involvement of third parties. We have carefully selected these third parties and taken steps to ensure that your Personal Information is adequately protected.

Google Analytics. You can prevent Google Analytics cookies from being stored by setting your browser software accordingly (see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-2) for further information). However, please note that you may not then be able to make full use of all the Website's functions.

You can also opt-out of Google Analytics by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

Sharing to Service Providers. We may share your Personal Information with our third party service providers based in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) who we engage to process the information that we collect from you on the Website, and/or to host and maintain our Website, content or services, on our behalf and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We will let you know if we need to transfer your Personal Information to any third party service providers located outside of the EEA.

Where we employ third party companies or individuals to process Personal Information provided by us (and not collected by them), they only use this Personal Information on our behalf and in line with our instructions and this Privacy Policy.

Sharing with other third parties. We may also provide your information to other third parties such as regulators and law enforcement agencies, where we are required by law to do so, where necessary for the purposes of preventing and detecting fraud, other criminal offences and/or to ensure network and information security.

Our Website offers the possibility to share content on social media channels, e.g., Facebook. The respective social media provider will directly gather Personal Information only after you click on the corresponding sharing button. Please refer to the privacy policy of the social media providers to learn more about what Personal Information is collected and used.

#### Your rights

At any time you can:

  * access, confirm, correct, rectify, update, supplement, anonymise, block, restrict or delete your Personal Information;
  * object to our use of your Personal Information;
  * know more about our processing of your Personal Information; or
  * transfer your Personal Information from us to another person or business.

In any of the cases above, please e-mail us at [secretariat@icfo.eu](mailto:secretariat@icfo.eu) or send us a letter to:  
ICFO-Institut de Ciències Fotòniques  
Av. Carl Friedrich Gauss, 3  
08860-Castelldefels (Barcelona), Spain

#### Amendments to the Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy has been approved by ICFO. ICFO reserves the right to amend this policy in the future in accordance with its own criteria or in response to any legislative or judicial development. In the event of an amendment, the updated policy will be published on the ICFO website and each particular case will be governed by the policy in rigor at the time the website was accessed.

#### Additional information

Security. Our Website is hosted on servers in the EEA. We employ appropriate security measures to help protect your Personal Information and guard against access by unauthorised persons. Information storage is on secure computers in a locked information centre and information is encrypted wherever possible. However, as the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our Website.

Confidentiality. We acknowledge that the information you provide may be confidential. We do not sell, rent, distribute or otherwise make Personal Information commercially available to any third party, except that we may share information with our service providers for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will maintain the confidentiality of and protect your information in accordance with our Privacy Policy and all applicable laws.

### COOKIES POLICY

Our Website uses a technology called “cookies” for the purpose of making it easier for you to browse the Website, distinguishing you from other users, providing you with a better experience when using the site, and identifying problems in order to improve our Website.

In accordance with the information supplied in the pop-up banner on the Website the first time you visit, when you browse and continue on our Website we will understand that you are consenting to the use of cookies as set out above and under the conditions contained in this Cookies Policy. Likewise, you will also be offered the possibility of accepting cookies expressly by clicking on the “accept” button provided in the aforementioned pop-up banner.

This Cookies Policy is aimed at informing you clearly and precisely about the cookies that are used on our Website.

#### Cookies: What are they?

A cookie is a file that is downloaded onto your equipment (computer or mobile device) for the purpose of storing data, which can be updated and retrieved by the body responsible for its installation.

The information collected by the cookies may include the date and time of visit to the Website, the pages viewed, the period of time you have been on our Website and the sites visited just before and after.

Cookies used by us are stored on your equipment for a maximum period of 2 years from the date when they are initially installed or if they are subsequently updated, from the date of the update.

##### Type of cookies used on the website

Authentication/Session

EZSESSID + hash for security reason (configurable), e.g.: "eZSESSIDf4749f6f95f4ac08f39385"

We use this cookie to allow user login and access to restricted areas of the Website and to recommend appropriate content.

Preferred Language/Localisation

ur_ui

We use this cookie to store information about the language and localisation preferences selected by the user.

Localisation and Routing

dpcms_show_message

We use this cookie to record whether or not a message has been displayed to inform the user (on his/her first visit) that the Website will direct the user to the page relevant to his/her location, or if location cannot be automatically determined, the international page.

Google Analytics

_ga  
_gat  
__utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmt  
__utmv  
__utmz

We use Google Analytics cookies to collect aggregate statistical information on the number of users accessing the Website and how they use it, including how they access the Website, the length and frequency of visits and pages viewed. We use this information to create reports and improve the Website. For more information about Google Analytics cookies please click [here](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/). To learn more about how we use Google Analytics please refer to our [Privacy Policy](https://www.icfo.eu/privacy-policy/#privacy-1).  
You can prevent transmission of the data created by Google Analytics cookies to Google and processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available [here.](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl+en)

#### Disabling and blocking cookies

You can block or disable cookies by activating the setting on your browser that lets you reject the installation of all cookies or some of them. Most browsers allow you to receive a warning that there are cookies or to reject them automatically.

If you reject the cookies, you will be able to continue using our Website, although you may have limited use of some of its services and therefore your experience on our Website will be less satisfactory.

You also can manage your cookies preferences using the following links for some of the most popular internet browsers:

To find out more about using your browser settings to control cookies please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

If you wish to withdraw, at any time, your consent regarding this Cookies Policy, you must delete the cookies stored on your equipment (computer or mobile device) via the preferences and settings of your internet browser.

Unless you have adjusted your browser settings, our system will create cookies as soon as you visit our Website. Bear in mind that most internet browsers let you change those settings.

#### Amendments to the Cookies Policy

We may change our Cookies Policy from time to time and this will be communicated to you when published via the “Cookies Policy” section located on the home page of the Website
